Chandani Shrestha, Ph.D.

Harrisonburg, VA 22807 shrestcx@jmu.edu

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interest is in Human-Computer Interaction, where I explore the potential of technology - 1) to promote *conscientious* classroom discussions. My current active research involves the ThoughtSwap system, a tool that supplements classroom pedagogy to change the infrastructure for discourse in classrooms. 2) to change power dynamics for empowerment of people especially in marginalized communities. My research interests and projects bridge multiple academic disciplines, using interdisciplinary scholarships to solve problems as a computer scientist.

EDUCATION

Graduate

Virginia Tech UniversityBlacksburg, VA *PhD in Computer Science and Applications*Fall, 2015 - Fall, 2022

Undergraduate

Benedict CollegeColumbia, SC *Bachelor of Science in Computer Science*Fall, 2011 – Fall, 2015

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

James Madison University Assistant Professor 2022 - Current

Fall 2022:

CS 149 - Intro to Programming in Python

Spring 2022:

CS 149 - Intro to Programming in Python

Fall 2023:

CS 149 - Intro to Programming in Python CS 447 - Interaction Design

Spring 2023:

CS 149 - Intro to Programming in Python CS 159 - Advanced Programming

Virginia Tech University

Blacksburg, VA Future Professoriate Certificate Fall, 2015 - Fall, 2022

Al Akhawayn University

Ifrane, Morocco Student Exchange Ambassador Fall, 2013

TALKS

Panelist (CAPWIC 2023)- Designing Apps for Diversity: Building Bridges through Mobile and Web App Development.

Technical Talk (CAPWIC 2023)- ThoughtSwap: Reinfrastructuring Classroom Discourse to promote Conscientious Discourse.

PUBLICATIONS

Chandani Shrestha, Deborah G. Tatar, Aakash Gautam, Michael Stewart. Reinfrastructuring Classroom Discourse with ThoughtSwap. The International Conference on Computer-Supported Collaborative Learning (CSCL) 2022

Chandani Shrestha, Deborah G. Tatar. Activating Conscientious Discussions in Classrooms Using ThoughtSwap. Proceedings of Conference on Higher Education Pedagogy 2020

Aakash Gautam, Michael Stewart, **Chandani Shrestha**, Javier Tibau, Steve Harrison, Deborah Tatar. Designing to Reflect Our Better Nature. Workshop Demo for ACM Designing Interactive Systems (DIS) 2019

Chandani Shrestha, Deborah Tatar, Christian Matheis, Steve Harrison, Michael Stewart. Position paper: ThoughtSwapping for in-depth and empathic co-located discussion. ACM Conference On Computer-Supported Cooperative Work And Social Computing (CSCW) 2018

Deborah G. Tatar, Michael Stewart, **Chandani Shrestha**. Promoting conscientious discussions in computer science ethics instruction. Journal of Computing Sciences in Colleges archive Volume 34 Issue 3, January 2019 (Best Poster Presentation - faculty/graduate student category)

Aakash Gautam, **Chandani Shrestha**, Steve Harrison, Deborah Tatar .Social Photo-Elicitation: The Use of Communal Production of Meaning to Hear a Vulnerable Population. Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction - CSCW archive Volume 2 Issue CSCW, November 2018

Aakash Gautam, **Chandani Shrestha**, Deborah Tatar. Beyond saving: a case for agency-first approach against domestic violence. ICTD '19 Proceedings of the Tenth International Conference on Information and Communication Technologies and Development

Swapna Thorve, **Chandani Shrestha** and Na Meng. An Empirical Study of Flaky Tests in Android Apps, International Conference on Software Maintenance and Evolution (ICSME) 2018

Aakash Gautam, **Chandani Shrestha**, Andrew Kulak, Steve Harrison, Deborah Tatar. Participatory Tensions in Working with a Vulnerable Population, PDC '18 Proceedings of the 15th Participatory Design Conference

Yufeng Ma, Tingting Jiang, **Chandani Shrestha**, Edward Alan Fox, Jian Wu, Clyde Lee Giles. Scenarios for Advanced Services in an ETD Digital Library, ETD2017, the 20th international symposium on electronic theses and dissertation

Chandani Shrestha, Hong Jiang. Customized Multimedia Google form for Education – A User Friendly Approach. In the proceeding of the 16th International Conference on Internet Computing, July, 2015, USA. p91-94. [Program Book, Proceeding Content, Proceeding Papers]

SERVICES and RECOGNITIONS

Organizing Committee - CAPWIC conference, 2023

Organizing Committee - JMU DIGITAL Conference, 2023

PhD Research Award - Virginia Tech, Computer Science, 2022

Kirk and Noel Schulz Transformative Graduate Education Fellowship, 2021-22

Graduate School nominee for the GTA Excellence-Assistant Award, 2021

Associate with Virginia Tech Academy for Graduate Teaching Assistant Excellence (VTGrATE), 2020 - 2022

Volunteer - Blacksburg Refugee Partnership, 2019 - 2020

Best Poster presentation (Faculty/ Graduate Student Category) - CCSC Eastern Conference, 2018

Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Scholar, 2015

Trustee Scholarship, Benedict College, 2011-2015

Anita Borg Systers Pass-It-On Awards, 2014

Google Scholarship, ACM Richard Tapia Celebration of Diversity in Computing, 2014